safecu.org 2004-12-06

# SAFE Credit Union - Privacy Policy

**Effective on:** 8/24/04

SAFE Credit Union and SAFE Financial Services have created this privacy policy in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to consumer privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the [www.safecu.org](http://www.safecu.org/) website. SAFE Credit Union is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to enable individuals and organizations to establish trusting relationships based on respect for personal identity and information by promoting the use of fair information practices. 

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact the SAFE Call Center by telephone at 1-800-733-7233, or email us at [callcenter@safecu.org](mailto:callcenter@safecu.org). If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry is not satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe through the [TRUSTe Watchdog Dispute Resolution Process](http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php). TRUSTe will serve as a liaison with the Web site to resolve users concerns. 

Back to Top

  * SAFE Credit Union and SAFE Financial Services Corporation are committed to protecting your privacy at all times. 
  * We do not share your information with non-affiliated third parties for purposes of selling their products and services to you. 
  * We are committed to bringing you the services you need to succeed financially. If SAFE Credit Union, SAFE Financial Services Corporation or our affiliates do not offer a financial service, such as certain insurance products, a joint marketing agreement is established which includes strict privacy protections. 
  * Your information is protected by strong security controls surrounding our technology and personnel. 

Back to Top

We restrict access to personal information about you to those employees who have a specific business purpose in utilizing your data. Our employees are trained in the importance of maintaining confidentiality and member privacy. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulations to guard your personal information. We will continue to test and update our technology to improve the protection of our information about you. This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. We use state-of-the-art SSL encryption technology to ensure your data is secured during transmission.  

Back to Top

We collect information about you to provide competitive financial products and services. Information is collected from the following sources: 

  * If you apply for membership online, we may collect the name of a family member who is an existing SAFE Credit Union member for the purpose of establishing membership eligibility.
  * Information on applications and other forms received from you, including your contact information, such as your name, address, email; sensitive information, such as your social security number, driver's license number; demographic information, such as your date of birth; and financial information such as your income. 
  * Information about your transactions with SAFE Credit Union, SAFE Financial Services Corporation, our affiliates XCU Capital Corporation and Focus Insurance Agency or others, including those companies that work closely with SAFE to provide you with financial products and services, such as your account balances, credit card usage, the parties to a transaction, or your payment history.
  * Information received from a credit-reporting agency, such as your creditworthiness and credit history.
  * Information obtained when verifying the information you provide on an application or other forms (this may be obtained from your current or past employers, or from other institutions where you conduct financial transactions), such as your payment history, information concerning your transactions and income.
  * Information obtained from consumer purchasing and census data providers, marketing researchers and public records, such as your income, home ownership, and marital status to develop competitive marketing programs for our members. 
  * We use your IP address and aggregate log file statistics to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our web site. Your IP address, etc. is used to help identify you. 
  * Cookies are electronic markers that are stored directly on the computer you are using to indicate activity or access to a specific web site or pages contained on a web site. When you return to our web site, your browser will give that information back to our server. We use cookies to maintain the state of your session on our web site and to store your computer's configuration data. This cookie data is tied to your personally identifiable information to enable our service. If you disable cookies on the computer you are using, you will not be able to bank online with us [or access our web site]. We do not encode your personally identifiable information in our cookies. Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. 
  * Our site's applications and forms require users to give us contact information (such as name and e-mail address) and financial information (e.g. account numbers). The member's contact information is used to contact the visitor for the purposes of account maintenance, customer service or dissemination of product & service information. 
  * We have calculator functions on the site that allow you to calculate different financial scenarios. These are stand-alone functions and are not tied to you or your personal information so when you use these functions, we do not collect, capture or retain your personal information. 
  * This site may contain links to other sites. SAFE Credit Union and SAFE Financial Services Corporation are is not responsible for the collection and use practices of nonaffiliated third parties to which our web site may link or for the content of such web sites. 
  * Our site uses forms for members to request information, products, and services. We collect your financial information (e.g. account or credit card numbers) and other personal information only as necessary to respond to your request or perform according to your instructions. Financial information that is collected is used to check the user's qualifications. 
  * Our site collects personally identifiable information from you when you perform transactions using our Bill Pay application. This information is used exclusively to fulfill the requested transaction. 
  * Our site uses chat functionality to facilitate communication between members and specially trained call center agents. Chat sessions may be archived as a means of review for customer service quality. Chat sessions are held to the same privacy standards as teller or telephone transactions and certain banking transactions are not permitted through chat due to the limitations of online authentication. 
  * If you do not interact with us when you browse our web site anonymously, we do not collect your personal information including your e-mail address. We may, however, gather data that is not personally identifiable to you such as length of user visit, number of hits and pages visited to evaluate the usefulness of our web site. 
  * If a user wishes to enroll in our email subscription list, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. Out of respect for our users privacy we provide a way to opt-out of these communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections. This information is not shared with any external business organizations. 

Back to Top

  * If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. 
  * If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. However, if users have opted out of all communication with the site, or deleted/deactivated their account, then they will not be contacted, nor will their personal information be used in this new manner. 

Back to Top

We share member information to provide superior service, tell you about new or enhanced financial services, and improve and develop our products and services. We may share the information described above with the following companies and as otherwise permitted by law: 

  * Companies that assist us in administering and bringing you our products and services. The information shared with these companies typically includes information to process transactions on your behalf, conduct our operations, and follow your instructions as you authorize, or protect the security of our financial records. These companies may include check and statement printing companies, and data processing vendors; however, these companies do not use your personal information for any secondary purposes. 
  * Businesses and other financial institutions with which we have a written joint marketing agreement to offer a broader array of offline products and services. Joint marketing agreements include confidentiality provisions to protect member information. These agreements prevent third parties from making your information available for any reason other than that which was intended. Examples of businesses with whom we have entered into joint marketing agreements include insurance companies; mortgage servicing companies and securities brokers/dealers. 
  * Companies that performs marketing or other business or professional services on our behalf such as businesses that perform mailing services or customer surveys. We have written agreements with these companies that include confidentiality provisions to protect member information. 
  * Consumer and credit reporting companies.
  * Our affiliates, XCU Capital Corporation, a securities broker/dealer and Focus Insurance Agency, an insurance agency, acting with our wholly owned subsidiary, SAFE Financial Services, in order to fulfill financial investment transactions such as, annuities, mutual funds, stocks and bonds, and insurance. 
  * There are other situations when we may disclose to third parties your personally identifiable information when permitted or required by law such as in response to legal process or to government entities or when you have requested us to share information about you with a third party.

Back to Top

We will not share information collected about former members or non-members, except as may be permitted or required by law. Email information about former members is held for re-marketing purposes unless the user has un-subscribed. If you would like to un-subscribe, [click here](http://www.safecu.org/content/information/contact.asp#subunsub). 

Back to Top

From our web site, we do not knowingly collect or use personal information from children under 13 without obtaining verifiable consent from their parents. Should a child whom we know to be under 13 send us personal information, we will only use that information to respond directly to that child, seek parental consent, or provide parental notice. We are not responsible for the data collection and use practices of non-affiliated third parties to which our web site might link. When linking to the SAFE Young Member's Club on our web site, you will be taken to the Googolplex web site operated by CUNA & Affiliates. Please review the PRIVACY POLICY located on the web site for specific information related to the Googolplex online magazine. For more information about the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), visit the FTC web site: [www.ftc.gov](http://www.ftc.gov/)

Back to Top

All SAFE members have a responsibility to Safeguard their financial information. 

  * Protect your account numbers, PINs (personal identification numbers) and passwords. Never keep your PIN with your debit or credit card, which can provide free access to your accounts if your card is lost or stolen. 
  * Use caution when disclosing your account numbers, social security numbers, etc. to other persons. If someone calls you, explains the call is on behalf of the credit union and asks for your account number, do not divulge that information. Official credit union staff will have access to your information and will not need to ask for it. 
  * Keep your information current. It is important that SAFE have current information on how to reach you. 
  * If your address or phone number changes, write to SAFE at the address below, or call us at (916) 979-7333 or (800) 733-7233. SAFE Credit Union   
P.O. Box 1057  
North Highlands, CA 95660-1057 
  * If SAFE detects potentially fraudulent or unauthorized activity or use of an account, SAFE will attempt to contact you immediately. For questions concerning identity theft and fraud, contact us at 916-971-2267.

Back to Top

If you would like to opt-out of future insurance solicitations from CUNA Mutual, please follow the steps below:

  * [Click here](mailto:onlinesupport@safecu.org) to send us an e-mail. 
  * Enter "Privacy Policy Opt-out" in the subject line. 
  * Enter your name and mailing address in the body of the e-mail message.
  * Click the "Send" button.

To opt-out of promotional e-mail messages from SAFE, please follow the steps below:

  * [Click here](mailto:onlinesupport@safecu.org) to send us an e-mail. 
  * Enter "Marketing Promotions Opt-out" in the subject line. 
  * Enter your name and mailing address in the body of the e-mail message.
  * Click the "Send" button.  

 ****

**Other Choices regarding your personal information on the Internet**

If you would like to reduce the amount of advertising you receive from other companies, visit the website [www.dmaconsumers.org](http://www.dmaconsumers.org/) or write to the following agencies and include your name, address and telephone number:  **Mail Preference Service**  
c/o Direct Marketing Association  
P.O. Box 643  
Carmel, NY 10512  **Telephone Preference Service**  
c/o Direct Marketing Association  
P.O. Box 1559  
Carmel, NY 10512  ****

To reduce the amount of email advertising, use the opt-out service at [www.dmaconsumer.org](http://www.dmaconsumer.org/).

If you would like to have your name taken off all pre-approved credit solicitations, call (888) 567-8688 or write to the following credit reporting agencies and include your name, address and Social Security Number:

**Experian**  
**Consumer Opt-out**  
P.O. Box 919  
Allen, TX 75013  
[www.experian.com](http://www.experian.com/) **Options Equifax, Inc**  
Equifax, Inc  
P.O. Box 740123  
Atlanta, GA  
30374-0123  
[www.equifax.com](http://www.equifax.com/) **Trans Union Corp**  
Name Removal Option  
P.O. Box 97328  
Jackson, MS  
39288-7328  
[www.tuc.com](http://www.tuc.com/) Or, you may call (888) 567-8688.  **National Do-Not-Call Registry**  
You can reduce the number of unwanted phone calls to your home by calling 1-888-382-1222 or registering your phone number at [www.fcc.gov/cgb/donotcall](http://www.fcc.gov/cgb/donotcall). 

Back to Top
